# Georgios Vavouliotis | Curriculum Vitae

Travessera de Les Corts 37, 08028 - Barcelona - Spain

## **Profile**

I earned my diploma on Electrical and Computer Engineering Department of National Technical University of Athens (NTUA). During my studies, I completed numerous projects that gave me a solid background in Computer Science and Software Engineering. Currently, I am a 3rd year Ph.D. student in Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) and Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS). My supervisors are Dr. Marc Casas Guix from BSC-CNS and Dr. Lluc Alvarez from UPC. Moreover, I collaborate with Prof. Daniel A. Jiménez from Texas A&M University and Prof. Boris Grot from University of Edinburgh. Finally, my research aims at building microarchitectural prefetching mechanisms that inherently use artificial intelligence algorithms.

## **Areas of Interest**

- Computer Architecture
- Artificial Intelligence

- System Software
- Operating Systems

#### **Education**

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)

Barcelona

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.)

Leveraging Artificial Intelligence Algorithms for Hardware Prediction

September 2018-now

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Diploma on Electrical & Computer Engineering, 300 ECTS, GPA: 8.9/10

2012-March 2018

#### Academic Directions.....

- Computer Systems & Software
- Computer Networks and Networks Security
- Signal Processing, Automatic Control and Robotics

#### Diploma Thesis.

Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms, GPA: 10/10

General Lyceum, Chalkida, Greece

Chalkida

Apolytirion, Top 0.1% in National Qualification Exams, GPA: 19.5/20

2009-2012

# Research Experience

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

Barcelona

Research Student

September 2018-now

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

Research Student on Computer Systems Laboratory (CSLab)

February 2018-July 2018

## **Participation in Projects**

SOW 5.3 - Intel and BSC-CNS Collaboration

Barcelona

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

**High Performance Computing VII** 

Barcelona

Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS)

September 2018-now

#### **Publications**

[1] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Goumas Georgios, "Performance Analysis of TLB Prefetching Mechanisms". Book of my diploma thesis.

- [2] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Cost-Effective Instruction TLB Prefetching*. Second Young Architect Workshop (YArch 2020). In conjunction with The 25th ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS 2020), Lausanne.
- [3] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Vasileios Karakostas, Konstantinos Nikas, Nectarios Koziris, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Exploiting Page Table Locality for Agile TLB Prefetching*. Submitted to 48th International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA) [under review].
- [4] **Georgios Vavouliotis**, Lluc Alvarez, Boris Grot, Daniel A. Jimenez, Marc Casas Guix, *Morrigan:* **A Composite Instruction TLB Prefetcher**. Submitted to 48th International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA) [under review].

# **Seminars and Training Courses**

#### **Summer Schools**

- Participation in accredited Summer Schools (certification provided)
  - HPC Architectures for Artificial Intelligence and Dedicated Applications

    Provided by ACM-Europe, 17 24 July 2019

#### **Seminars**

- Participation in accredited seminars (certification provided)
  - Introduction to Heterogenous Memory Usage
  - Provided by **PACT BSC-CNS**, 26 February 2019

#### Online Courses (MOOCs)

Courses offered by accredited universities and training programs (certification provided)

#### **Machine Learning**

Provided by Stanford University (Prof. Andrew Ng), May 2018 - July 2018, GPA: 10/10

- · Supervised Learning (Regression Models, SVMs, NN)
- · Unsupervised Learning (Clustering, Dimensionality Reduction)

#### **Advanced Programming with Python**

- Provided by Mathesis Online Platform, March 2018 April 2018, GPA: 10/10
  - · Object Oriented Programming
  - · Data Storage (sqlite3, pickle, JSON)
  - · Graphic Interface Programming and Game Development

# **Teaching Experience**

Private Tutor Athens

During my Diploma I was giving private lectures to:

2013-2018

## **Undergraduate students of Computer Science Department**

C programming, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Automatic Control

#### High school students

Mathematics, Physics

#### Lab Assistant at National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Athens

C programming, Operating Systems

2013-2017

## **Technical and Personal skills**

#### Programming Languages:

- Proficient: C, Python,
- Basic knowledge: C++, Matlab-Simulink, Assembly (8085, 8086, AVR), R, Prolog, SML/NJ, Java

#### Software Skills:

- Proficient: Unix Bash, LATEX
- Basic knowledge: Git, MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript,
   CACTI, TCL AWK Wireshark

#### Simulators:

Proficient: ChampSimBasic knowledge: Gem5

## Operating Systems:

- Proficient: Linux, Mac OS, Windows

#### General Business Skills:

- Ability to work with a team
- Very good presentation skills
- Able to write well organized and structured reports

## **Honors and Awards**

#### 2019 FPI Doctoral Fellowship

**Barcelona** 

Funded by Spanish Government (MINECO)

2019-2022

Mathematics Award - National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

Excellent marks in all mathematical courses during the first two (2) years.

Athens 2014

"The Great Moment of Education" Eurobank EFG Scholarship

Chalkida

O Highest rank in National Qualifications Exams in my school - 1000 Euros

2012

## **Affiliations**

- Affiliated PhD student in HiPEAC (European Network of Excellence on High Performance and Embedded Arcitecture and Compilation)
- o IEEE member

# Languages

- o **Greek** (Native) o **Italian** (Beginner)
- English (B2 (FCE, KPG)) Spanish (Beginner)

# Personal Interests and extra-curricular activity

ChallengesWritingCookingBasketballCinema

#### References

References available upon request.